<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-31T17:10:55+01:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gilmore Girls Blog</title><subtitle>Let&apos;s talk Gilmore Girls.  Whether you&apos;ve just discovered the show or you&apos;re on  your bazillionth re-watch, we understand.  You NEED to talk about it.  With a village  who understands.  We&apos;ve got you.  Welcome to Gilmore Girls Blog.   </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to have images display in Feedly thumbnails</title><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/31/rss-images-test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to have images display in Feedly thumbnails" /><published>2025-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/31/rss-images-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/31/rss-images-test/"><![CDATA[<p>So there’s the coffee image in the yaml front material.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="testing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So there’s the coffee image in the yaml front material.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/maple_coffee.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/maple_coffee.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s your favourite Gilmore Girls scene?</title><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/What's-your-favourite-Gilmore-Girls-scene/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What’s your favourite Gilmore Girls scene?" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/What&apos;s%20your%20favourite%20Gilmore%20Girls%20scene</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/What&apos;s-your-favourite-Gilmore-Girls-scene/"><![CDATA[<p>My chain of thoughts was interrupted today by a colleague asking me what I was thinking about.  I’d been away with the fairies, a dappy smile on my face.  ”Favourite pizza”, I replied - my go-to - but actually I was replaying Gilmore Girls scenes in my head.</p>

<p><strong>What’s your favourite scene from Gilmore Girls?</strong>  It’s a difficult - possibly impossible - question to answer.  Favorite in what way?  For all the reasons you’re here reading about a show that ended five years ago.  Something sweet but honest?  Something that gave you a perspective on growing up or parenting?  Some inspired kookiness that just made you laugh when you needed it?  Perhaps all the above.  I like a challenge and I’m not scared of getting shot down.  So here are my close contenders:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>From the pilot, Lorelai and Rory argue, then simultaneously put on Macy Gray’s CD.  It’s amusing and clever and perfectly pitches us the overlap in their temperaments.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Luke’s horoscope and declaration: He’s all in / “Would you just stand still?”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Stars Hollow’s fairwell to Rory, where Melissa McCarthy is barely holding it together</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Hole. HOLE. Hole – dirt… bed, dirt? HOLE.” I’m paraphrasing here.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But in this thirty second window between typing and posting, if I had to pick my absolute favourite scene, it’s Lorelai sweeping pizza crusts under the sink – and getting caught by Rory.  It’s got their role reversal, abuse of the kitchen and it’s just a damn funny thing to do.</p>

<p><strong>Too hard? How about two favourite scenes from your top ten?</strong><br />
<strong>Anyone else wonder how bad the takeout from Al’s Pancake World really is?</strong>  I only ask because I’m hankering for a chow mein sandwich right now.<br />
<strong>What’s your favourite pre-credits scene?</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="archive" /><category term="editorial" /><category term="hypothetical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My chain of thoughts was interrupted today by a colleague asking me what I was thinking about. I’d been away with the fairies, a dappy smile on my face. ”Favourite pizza”, I replied - my go-to - but actually I was replaying Gilmore Girls scenes in my head.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/s02e05%20lake.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/s02e05%20lake.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Great Loves of Gilmore Girls : Lorelai and… snow</title><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/The-Great-Loves-of-Gilmore-Girls-Lorelai-and-snow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Great Loves of Gilmore Girls : Lorelai and… snow" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/The%20Great%20Loves%20of%20Gilmore%20Girls%20Lorelai%20and%20snow</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/28/The-Great-Loves-of-Gilmore-Girls-Lorelai-and-snow/"><![CDATA[<p>She glides downstairs in a red long-sleeved tee and pulls the sash window open, hangs her head out and breathes in the chilly air. It’s a moment of care-free innocent enjoyment and Lauren, with her hair in bunches, is so cute it’s almost annoying (‘how can you be so adorably cherubic?!’ I want to shout, pinching her porcelain cheeks, tears streaming down mine). You kinda get the feeling Lauren Graham does this kind of thing for real while Peter Krause rolls his eyes; she’s effortless.</p>

<p>Hey wait up, there are no curtains in the living room either!  What’s the deal with that?  Back to clipping coupons, Lorelai.  So anyway, with the icy wind blowing the netting around, she finds a spot on the sofa and replays Max’s bashful answerphone message (“It’s Max. Medina. Maaax Medina”) and on the second playthrough, it wakes Rory up.  Like any sane person, Rory goes to close the window because it’s freezing and rolls her eyes when Lorelai stops her and begins her first diatribe on her love affair with snow.  Because she can smell it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Lorelai</strong>  Everything’s magical when its snows, everything looks pretty. The clothes are great. Coats, scarves, gloves, hats.
<strong>Rory</strong>  Thermal underwear, wool socks. Ear flaps.
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  Do you know the best things in my life have happened when it snowed?
<strong>Rory</strong>  Why yes, I do.
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  My best birthday.
<strong>Rory</strong>  Your first kiss.
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  Your first steps, they all happened when it snowed. 
<strong>Rory</strong>  Feet. <br />
[Lorelai pulls her feet up onto the sofa and Rory covers them with the throw]
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  I feel good. Tingly.
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  That’s called frostbite.
<span class="episode-ref">s01e08 Love and War and Snow</span></p>
</blockquote>

<p>And after Rory goes back to bed, Lorelai hides under the blanket and listens to Max’s message again.  Ah, new love.
I love snow too and it’s been snowing here.  It’s magical and Christmassy and jogs some of my favourite, funnest memories.  SNOWING!!!</p>

<p>Of course every relationship has its difficulties.  Later on - in season 5 - words are exchanged in anger when the weather causes cancellations at the inn and blocking in her Jeep.  It’s a one-sided conversation:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/gg-s05e11 snow2.PNG" alt="Lorelai rages at the weather" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Lorelai</strong>  Me and snow, we are through. It was years of bliss y’know, we had good stuff and good times. I could show you pictures of snow angels I’ve made but I am done! Done!!
<strong>Luke</strong>  Well, let it down easy OK?
<span class="episode-ref">s05e11 Women Of Questionable Morals</span></p>
</blockquote>

<p>At least she has Luke, who later brokers peace between Lorelai and weather… with a homemade ice rink to chill out on.</p>

<p>Happy Holidays to all our Gilmore News readers.  Keep Warm and Best Wishes for 2013!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="archive" /><category term="editorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[She glides downstairs in a red long-sleeved tee and pulls the sash window open, hangs her head out and breathes in the chilly air. It’s a moment of care-free innocent enjoyment and Lauren, with her hair in bunches, is so cute it’s almost annoying (‘how can you be so adorably cherubic?!’ I want to shout, pinching her porcelain cheeks, tears streaming down mine). You kinda get the feeling Lauren Graham does this kind of thing for real while Peter Krause rolls his eyes; she’s effortless.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/gg-s01e08%20snow1.PNG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/gg-s01e08%20snow1.PNG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Would Rory Gilmore have a Kindle?</title><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/Would-Rory-Gilmore-have-a-Kindle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Would Rory Gilmore have a Kindle?" /><published>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/Would%20Rory%20Gilmore%20have%20a%20Kindle</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/Would-Rory-Gilmore-have-a-Kindle/"><![CDATA[<p>There’s that episode where she’s berating her backpack for being too miniscule for her library of books. It’s bursting at the seams. On top of her school books, she’s packed a bus book (Milay’s biography), a lunch book (Vidal’s essays), a Faulkner novel and Eudora Welty’s short stories, for whichever mood might take her.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Rory</strong>  No, the Milay is a biography, and sometimes if I’m on the bus and I pull out a biography and I think to myself, “Well, I don’t really feel like reading about a person’s life right now” then I’ll switch to the novel, and then sometimes if I’m not into the novel, then I’ll switch back.<br />
<strong>Lorelai</strong>  Hold on. What is the Gore Vidal?<br />
<strong>Rory</strong>  Oh that’s my lunch book.<br />
<span class="episode-ref">s02e07 Like Mother Like Daughter</span></p>
</blockquote>

<p>On an e-book reader, I switch between books like I’m switching between channels. I’m kind of the same with real books, I can be halfway through one when I’ll start another - then another, using the second as a bookmark for the first etc. until I start closing them out in reverse order, like parentheses. But what would Rory do? Here’s my hypothetical…</p>

<p>I’m envisaging some well-meaning family friend - let’s say Babette - receives a Kindle as a gift and since the old broad doesn’t read so good any more, she gives it to Lorelai to pass onto Rory (who now lives in New York) because everyone knows Rory’s an eternal bookaholic. Initially repulsed by the thing because it doesn’t smell like a book, you can’t flick to a spot you remember, you can’t personalise it or lend it or accidentally spill coffee on it, Rory intends to re-gift it but it stays on the credenza until one day she’s in a rush, doesn’t have anything to read and grabs it on the way out, as a last resort. She returns home that night (to Jess, who now wears thick-rimmed black glasses while he types magazine articles and occasional novels on a second-hand typewriter at a second-hand wooden desk in their cosy low-ceilinged New York loft apartment) and she’s converted - nay, evangelistic.</p>

<p>She tells him while riding the subway she bought twenty books out of thin air, another twenty while sitting in the park at lunchtime and six more on a bathroom break. She’s now carrying FIFTY new books in her beat-up Birkin bag, she can type notes into the book and they’re synchronised online and she only has to remember to charge the thing every couple of weeks. She’s got the Kindle Keyboard 3G so she can surf or check her e-mail in an emergency, anywhere in the world, for free. <a href="http://xkcd.com/548/">It’s basically the Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy</a>.</p>

<p>Jess peers over his glasses, looking something between sceptical and worried. He says if it ain’t broke, don’t fix it - but as he puts on the coffee (using an old filter coffee maker he repaired from Luke’s), he’s just happy she’s happy.</p>

<p>I get the feeling an e-book reader wouldn’t solve her capacity problems because she’d carry it in addition to her other books, because sometimes she’d be in the mood for paper and the feel of a book, since she will always love books - but I think there’d still be a niche for an e-book due to the realisation that with all its plus points and non-book points, the best thing about a Kindle is when you have a good book on it. A good book is a good book. (Conversely, when I get a couple of bad books in a row, I tend to blame the device and go back to real books for a while).</p>

<p><strong>Do you think Rory’d love her Kindle?</strong> It’s gotta be a lighter way to attempt <a href="http://www.bookclubforum.co.uk/community/index.php?/topic/5203-rory-gilmores-book-list-challenge/">Rory Gilmore’s Book List Challenge</a>.<br />
<strong>Did Gilmore Girls ever inspire you to read anything?</strong><br />
<strong>Team Kindle or Paperback Diehard?</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="archive" /><category term="hypothetical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s that episode where she’s berating her backpack for being too miniscule for her library of books. It’s bursting at the seams. On top of her school books, she’s packed a bus book (Milay’s biography), a lunch book (Vidal’s essays), a Faulkner novel and Eudora Welty’s short stories, for whichever mood might take her.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/gg-busbook.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/gg-busbook.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh there you are, finally.</title><link href="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/its-been-a-while/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh there you are, finally." /><published>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/its-been-a-while</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/2025/03/23/its-been-a-while/"><![CDATA[<p>Right now I’m at the end of season three.  My sweet spot.  Jess is visiting his dad in Santa Monica.  Lorelai’s reading Rory’s yearbook and discovered that Rory is valedictorian but didn’t tell her.  She’s so proud you can see her eyes start to prickle but she doesn’t make a scene because Rory’s so busy revising and doesn’t have time.  I on the other hand, am a heaving, blubbering mess.</p>

<p>Wait though, let’s back up a moment.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong class="inline-strong">Hello.  I’m Rich and I am a Gilmore Girls fan.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>There’s a braindump of information about me and my history in the <a href="/about.html">About</a> page.</p>

<p>In short, I’m making a home for these old thoughts and scribbles.  Some have aged better than others.  Luckily, I wield complete editorial control.</p>

<p>It’s been a month since I put up the <a href="/snow.html">holding page</a> billboard and I’ve been slowly chipping away.  Designing and redesigning, coding and recoding.  I’m using jekyll hosted on github, learning as I go.  Having to decide every curve, corner and colour.  The limitations and control lend themselves to finding satisfying creative solutions almost as often as blundering into yet another butt-clenching mistake.  It’s not the obvious or easy way but I’m rolling around in the process like a happily curious pig in mud.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong class="inline-strong">I know how I want the blog to feel, more than how I want it to work.  That’s my guiding star.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Upcoming steps are to revive, re-jig and re-post some of the old texts, in roughly chronological order.  Tastefully nipping here and tucking there.  Also hoping to fire up an RSS feed, organise categories and create category pages.  And having a hack at adding comments or some kind of feedback buttons.</p>

<p>Until then it’ll be a kind of sporadically updated archive with periodic twaddle, like this.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fresh" /><category term="editorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right now I’m at the end of season three. My sweet spot. Jess is visiting his dad in Santa Monica. Lorelai’s reading Rory’s yearbook and discovered that Rory is valedictorian but didn’t tell her. She’s so proud you can see her eyes start to prickle but she doesn’t make a scene because Rory’s so busy revising and doesn’t have time. I on the other hand, am a heaving, blubbering mess.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/maple_coffee.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.gilmoregirlsblog.com/assets/images/maple_coffee.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>